<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scrolling Text</string>
    <string name="article_title">Grace Under Pressure</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">1984 Rush Album</string>
    <string name="article_text">
        \n\nIn July 1983, Rush (http://rush.com/) ended its 1982–1983 tour of North America and the UK in support of its previous album, Signals (1982). The group reconvened in mid-August to write and rehearse new material for a follow-up in a lodge in Horseshoe Valley in Barrie, Ontario. The sessions were productive, partly due to the set amount of time they gave themselves to work in and that studio time had already been booked. The band adopted its usual working method of Geddy Lee and Alex Lifeson working on music while Neil Peart worked on lyrics. News stories from the Toronto-based newspaper The Globe and Mail inspired some of the lyrics on the album, particularly "Distant Early Warning," "Red Lenses" and "Between the Wheels." Peart wrote that they came up with "Between the Wheels" on the first night and, after a few days, "Kid Gloves" and "Afterimage." In three weeks, the group had assembled a demo tape of the aforementioned tracks along with "Red Sector A" and "The Body Electric." Development then paused in September 1983 while Rush performed five nights at Radio City Music Hall in New York City, after which the band resumed album rehearsals.
        \n\nGrace Under Pressure is the first Rush album that was not produced by Terry Brown since its 1974 debut effort. At the beginning of the Signals tour in April 1982, Rush met with Brown in Miami to inform him that the band had decided to work with a different producer. The group wished to explore different approaches and techniques that someone else might offer which in turn would develop their sound but stressed that the change did not suggest any dissatisfaction in Browns production. Peart recalled that the split was tough for both parties considering the length of time they had worked together, but that they split on good terms. Brown receives a tribute in the liner notes of Grace Under Pressure in French which translates to "And always our good old friend."
        \n\nThe search for a new producer began during Rushs 1983 European tour, where the band met various individuals during their visit to the UK. They met Steve Lillywhite, who initially agreed to the project, but he backed out two weeks before the band was to start rehearsing, as he had decided to work with Simple Minds instead. They had Yes bassist Chris Squire and singer and producer Trevor Horn, who once sang in Yes, attend their concert at Wembley Arena with the prospect of choosing one of them to produce. Eventually, the group started pre-production alone, which Peart thought increased the bands desire to succeed: "This really drew us together and gave us a strong resolve and a mutual determination to make a really great record." Rush then met with another English producer during rehearsals who showed promise, but various problems that hindered his availability could not be solved in time. This was followed by the arrival of Englishman Peter Henderson, who the band liked and agreed to produce and engineer, but his occasional indecisiveness left the band to handle the majority of the creative decisions themselves. Despite this, Rush and Henderson are credited as co-producers in the liner notes.
        \n\nAfter a collection of demos had been worked out, the group entered Le Studio in Morin-Heights, Quebec to record, from November 1983 to March 1984, the longest period Rush had taken to record an album up to this point. The band spent up to 14 hours per day in the studio. In a 1984 interview, Lifeson picked Grace Under Pressure as the "most satisfying of all our records."
        \n\nA music video produced for "The Enemy Within" would be the first played by the Canadian music television channel MuchMusic, which launched in August 1984.
    </string>
    <string name="add_comment">Add Comment</string>
</resources>
